[♪ upbeat music playing]
[narrator]
The special summer break Noel organized
for the Travis Japan members.
At the foot of the Rocky Mountains
where the desert winds blow
lies the real America
the members have yet to see.
-[exclaims]
-[Chaka gasps] Wow!
-Agreed!
-[all] Moab.
[Umi] You're driving on American roads!
[whistles]
-[in English] Let's go!
-Let's go!
Cheers!
[Genta whoops]
[narrator, in Japanese]
The Travis Japan members except for Noel
divide up into two groups
and follow his travel plans
across the American Southwest.
Their destination is Sedona, Arizona.
Noel sets out to Sedona on his own
before the others
to quietly prepare
a warm welcome for them.
[♪ upbeat music continues]
Travis Japan
SUMMER VACATION!! IN THE USA
[Genta, in Japanese]
Where are we headed today?
-[Shime] Let's consult Noel's itinerary.
-[Machu] Here it is.
"Today, you are visiting Santa Fe,
a city known as America's Gem."
-Santa Fe?
-Yeah.
"These unique buildings are made
with Native American techniques."
[Machu] Whoa.
-They're made of clay.
-[Machu] Whoa.
Ooh, I wonder if
it's the turquoise aesthetics.
-It's possible.
-That's awesome.
"Please enjoy America's
beautiful cityscape and fashion."
-[Genta] There!
-[Machu] Man, I'm excited.
-Whoa.
-Fashion gets me hyped up.
Genta likes Native American design.
-Right? Right?
-It's my thing.
[Machu] Let's go!
-[Genta] Time to get going.
-[Shime] Let's go, let's go.
-[Machu] Hup.
-[Shime] This is exciting.
-[Genta] I'll put your belongings away.
-[Machu] Oh, thanks.
[Genta] Thanks for driving, as always.
-[Machu] Leave it to me.
-[Shime] We're counting on you.
[Genta] What a tasty-looking cloud.
[Genta] The sky goes on forever!
[Machu] What a vast sky.
-[Shime] It's so open out here.
-[Machu] Yeah.
-[Machu] Isn't this liberating?
-[Genta] Yeah.
Just the fact the sky is so blue and vast…
puts me in a good mood.
[narrator, in English]
Santa Fe, New Mexico.
[in Japanese] This is one of
the oldest cities in the United States.
[Machu] I've seen scenery like this
inside theme parks.
-[Genta laughs] I've seen it too.
-Oh, me too.
[Genta] This is crazy.
Whoa. There's bags, clothes…
-I'm really enjoying the vibe here.
-It's a trendy place.
-[Shime] There are clothing stores.
-[Genta] I might really like it.
-[Shime] Yeah, I love the feel.
-[Genta] Whoa.
-Look. This is something else.
-This is great.
[Noel] When I set foot in Santa Fe
for the first time a couple of months ago,
I didn't think you'd fall in love with it.
This city is known for its art scene.
There's an eclectic culture with strong
Spanish and Native American influence.
I bet these would look great on Machu.
[Noel]
The style of the traditional jewelry
has been passed down
for thousands of years.
There's also the cowboy culture
reminiscent of the Old West.
Everywhere you look,
you'll find traces of various groups
that called this city home
through the ages.
And that's why I want you guys
to immerse yourselves
in the rich culture of this city.
[dashboard chimes]
-[Machu] Okay, we made it.
-[Shime, Genta] Thank you!
-Thanks, Machu.
-Thank you, Machu.
Okay!
[♪ upbeat country music playing]
[♪ music ends]
-Okay then…
-[Shime] Hmm…
Should we…
-Split up?
-Yeah?
-Let's do it.
-Okay.
-I want to go see turquoise jewelry.
I'll follow Gen-chan's lead.
-Wanna go see some turquoise?
-Yeah.
-Then I'll check out the hats here.
-Hats?
-See ya.
-Bye-bye, okay.
-Later.
-See you later.
[Shime, in Japanese]
There's a variety of shops here.
Yes.
But I do want something
made with turquoise.
Mm-hmm.
-Shall we look around?
-Okay.
-What a big store.
-[Shime laughs]
[♪ gentle music playing]
[in English] Let's go!
[narrator, in Japanese]
Shime and Genta's first stop…
-Whoa. This is amazing.
-…is a shop specializing
-in Native American jewelry.
-[Genta] These are really pretty.
Aren't they cute?
-Whoa, great design.
-They're great. [chuckles]
-Whoa, cute.
-Have you always been into this style?
Yeah. I don't know why…
Don't know why I'm drawn to it.
Huh.
Did you see it somewhere?
Maybe in a movie?
Not really, no… Oh, but I guess my family…
[Shime] Yes.
…was always into it.
-Oh, really?
-Yeah.
But I don't know
its historical background at all.
Thought it'd be fun
to learn more about it.
-That's true.
-Like learning about the makers and such.
Yes.
I don't know what makes
this style of jewelry appealing.
-Since I'm here, I can learn its history.
-Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
I want to learn more about it
as I shop around.
-What a great idea.
-You think so?
[in English] Panama Hats.
[in Japanese] Now this looks cool.
Wowza.
[narrator] Meanwhile, Machu heads
to an Old West-style shop.
[in English] Hi.
Hello, hello.
-[clerk 1] Welcome to the Montecristi.
-Thank you so much.
Yes, sir. How may we help you?
Oh, so I wanna look around the…
-Uh-huh.
-…that there.
-Ooh, it's really cool.
-Oh, yeah. This is the southwest.
[in Japanese] Whoa, its rim is so wide.
I love the way it looks.
-[in English] Hey!
-Hey! Like a cowboy! [chuckles]
[in Japanese] This is fantastic.
-[clerk 1, in English] That is fantastic.
-Whoa. Cute, cute.
[in Japanese] Huh, cute.
-[in English] These are concho belts.
-Uh-huh.
[chuckling, in Japanese] I would never
find a belt like this in Japan.
[in English] Like cowboy.
[in Japanese] Whoa, I look cool.
[clerk 1, in English] That's right.
-Okay. So, you got your hat on.
-Okay.
-You got your belt on.
-You're in the southwest.
-Okay.
You're ready to go… Pistols!
-Boom!
-Bang!
Smoke. Yeah.
Set.
Oh. [laughs]
-Yeah, man, cool.
-Cool.
-Yeah, oh, he's quick. He's very quick.
-[laughs]
[in Japanese] Yeah,
I'm a cowboy now. [laughs]
-"Yatta"?
-[in English] Thank you so much.
-It's a pleasure.
-[Machu laughs]
[in Japanese] Yes.
Um, I'd like to buy a hat.
[in English] Of course. Please.
First choice, if you wanna buy a hat,
will be material.
Whether it's Panama straw…
-Mm-hmm.
-…or fur felt.
-Panama.
-[Machu] Panama.
-[clerk 1] Warm weather.
-Mm-hmm.
-This is fur felt. This is animal fur.
-Mmm. Oh.
-It's for cold weather.
[in Japanese] I'd like the Panama-style.
[in English] So…
I wanna…
-Yeah, I wanna… Yeah.
-[clerk 1] Very nice. Okay.
All right. This is a Panama.
-It's ventilated, so it's very cool.
-Mmm.
-Protection here. Protection here.
-Mm-hmm.
Now, I think this is going to be
too small for you,
-but let's just start with that.
-Oh. Oh.
-[in Japanese] Oh, true.
-[in English] And… And it is.
-[in Japanese] It fits a little tight.
-[in English] Okay.
So now what we would need to do
-is to measure your head…
-Mm-hmm.
-…take a template of your head.
-Mm-hmm. Mmm.
-[in Japanese] It can be customized?
-[clerk 1, in English] Yes. Yes.
-Customized. Uh-huh.
-Yeah.
Now…
[Machu, in Japanese] Whoa, what's that?
[clerk 1, in Spanish] Old…
[in English] This is called a conformator.
-Very rare.
-Mmm.
Over 200 years old and it's still working.
-Oh.
-Uh-huh.
-Okay, look at my eyes.
-Okay.
-Whoa! [laughs]
-Yeah, man.
Okay.
[in Japanese] Whoa, that was quick.
[in English] Oh!
-Not only your size…
-Mm-hmm.
…but the shape of your head.
All righty.
[Machu, in Japanese]
Oh, I get how it works.
And now, he can make a hat
according to the template.
[narrator]
The hatmaker uses the measurements
and template of the head shape
to craft a hat.
The craftsman repeats the steaming and
drying process, slowly shaping the hat.
Whoa. This is cool.
This is what you'd call "handmade."
-This is amazing.
-[clerk 2, in English] Mm-hmm.
You wanna try?
-Yeah. I wanna try it.
-Okay.
-Put your hand here.
-Wow! Ah, okay.
[in Japanese] Whoa, amazing.
-[clerk 2, in English] No more steam.
-Okay.
Okay.
[in Japanese] And now…
-[in English] Like this?
-Yeah.
-[clerk 2] Very nice.
-Oh.
Okay, so we have the hat flat there--
[in Japanese] Oh! Whoa.
It's very flat now.
Whoa, now that's sleek.
[in English] So, you follow me up in here
to crease the hat.
-[in Japanese] I see, I see.
-All right.
[in English] Mmm. Mmm. Mmm. Mmm.
-We're good.
-Yeah.
That feels good. All right.
[steam hissing]
-[in Japanese] What the heck.
-[chuckles]
[Machu, in English] Yes. Mmm.
The hat has what we call sizing in it.
Which makes it stiff.
[Machu, in Japanese] Whoa, look at that!
[clerk 1, in English] Yeah. So here we go.
[steam hissing]
[Machu, in Japanese]
This is such an intricate process.
[steam hissing]
[Machu, in English] Okay, okay, okay.
[in Japanese]
I get it. You can shape the hat
-by steaming, then pressing.
-[in English] Yeah. Yeah.
-Yeah.
-Oh!
[mutters]
[in English] And now…
-And there.
-[in Japanese] Amazing.
[in English] Okay.
-We're good. Okay.
-Oh, well done.
-Now, we gotta do the rounding. Okay.
-Oh.
Now, what we're gonna do,
this is called a pencil curl.
[Machu, in Japanese] Pencil curl?
What is pencil curling?
[steam hissing]
[Machu] That's what it is.
[in English] I see, I see.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[Machu, in Japanese]
Whoa, he's such a pro.
[in English] I'm gonna put the iron down
for you right there.
-Okay. Okay.
-You're good to go.
All right. Yeah.
-[in Japanese] Like this… like this!
-[in English] Good. Good.
-Keep your arm flat. Like that, yeah.
-Okay, okay, okay.
-Like this?
-That's it. That's it.
[in Japanese] Ah. [laughs]
Hold on… What if I misshape it?
Hold on. I'm scared.
[in English] All right, this is it.
[in Japanese] Oh, the fit is perfect.
[chuckling] Ooh.
-[whistles, laughs]
-[in Spanish] You look great. [laughs]
-[in Japanese] I look amazing.
-[in English] Yeah.
Thank you so much.
So, I think all we need now is a hat band.
-Hat band. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
-Okay.
So, these are some bands
that we suggest. Bead work.
-Bead work.
-Oh.
Very vibrant.
See how small the bead work is?
-[Machu, in Japanese] How small.
-Those are very nice.
[in Japanese] Amazing.
-[clerk 1, in English] Porcupine quill.
-Porcupine.
[clerk 1] Very rare.
[Machu] Very rare.
[clerk 1] And horse hair.
[Machu] Mm-hmm.
-[exclaims]
-[clerk 1] Yeah.
I wanna try it. Yeah.
Okay. All right.
We'll go horse hair first.
This is something new.
This did not exist before.
[in Japanese] Amazing. The band makes
the hat look completely different.
[clerk 1, in English]
Now going this way we cannot sew it on.
-[Machu] Mm-hmm.
-But it's snug enough, you won't lose it.
[in Japanese] Oh, I like it. How charming.
Wait, I'm having trouble choosing.
Whoa.
[in English] Porcupine.
[Machu, in Japanese] How cool.
-I can't help but be drawn to rare things.
-[chuckles]
Whoa, I love this.
-[exclaims]
-[clerk 1, in English] Yeah?
-Yeah!
-[laughs]
[in Japanese] This is wonderful.
-[in English] Some bead work.
-Okay. Thank you.
[in Japanese] It's cute.
Oh, I can't pick.
[♪ music ends]
[in English] Uh…
-[in Japanese] This one please.
-[in English] Yeah.
-[Machu] Porcupine. Porcupine.
-Porcupine.
-It's very nice.
-[chuckles] Yeah.
[in Japanese] Yes!
[in English] Put this on you.
-And that is it right there.
-Mm-hmm.
-Wow!
-Uh-huh.
[in Japanese] This looks great!
-[in English] Thank you so much.
-It's a pleasure.
-Thank you. I appreciate it.
-Yes, sir.
[in Japanese] Whoo-hoo!
This is the best hat ever.
Getting to experience the crafting process
is so rare.
Now that I've seen the effort
that goes into hat-making,
I can have the same dedication
for my music.
I want to apply this experience
to my musical career.
This was an invaluable experience.
I'm very pleased.
[in English] We are so happy
-that you are pleased.
-Yeah.
-Thank you so much.
-It's a pleasure, sir.
Thank you.
-Thank you very much.
Very easy to carry.
Thank you so much.
And we look forward to serving you again…
-Okay. All right.
-…soon.
-Great work in your career.
-Okay.
Thank you very much.
Bang!
-Thank you so much. Thank you.
-And you, sir. Take care.
-Bye-bye. Thank you.
-It's a pleasure. See you. See you.
-Bye.
-Ciao.
Whoo!
[in Japanese]
This place might carry a wide selection.
They carry a whole bunch.
-Wanna check it out?
-Let's go in.
-They have a whole bunch.
-Whoa.
-Whoa, amazing.
-Whoa, this is cool.
[♪ gentle music playing]
There's an entire collection in here.
-[narrator] Shime and Genta visit…
-[Genta] How cool.
…another traditional
Native American jewelry shop.
This store seems to especially
focus on jewelry made with turquoise.
-[clerk, Shime, in English] Hello.
-[Genta] Nice to meet you.
[clerk] How are you?
-[Genta] Great.
-[Shime] Yeah, great.
-Good.
-[Shime] Yeah, yeah.
[Genta] And we… turquoise.
Uh, I can tell you a lot about turquoise.
There's many different types
of American turquoise.
[Genta, Shime] Uh-huh.
[clerk]
And the price can be very different.
Shall we… [in Japanese] Here.
[in English] Also, this. You made it?
-No.
-No?
-This piece is from 1950.
-[Genta] 1950?
This one is-is made, uh,
for only special, um, Diné, Navajo.
-Uh, the medicine men or the chiefs.
-Uh-huh.
So, this is the most expensive turquoise
in America.
It's called lander blue.
Oh, wow.
The most expensive turquoise because
only a small quantity came from the mine.
-It's a small quantity…
-[Genta] Uh-huh.
And everybody
loved the quality right away.
So, it became very expensive.
And the mine closed
more than 50 years ago,
-so that means the collectorship grows…
-[Genta] Fifty years old…
This is the great thing about turquoise.
-Is… There's a piece for everyone.
-Yeah.
They see what they like.
-Then I can tell you about the stone.
-Mmm. Mmm.
I can tell you about the maker.
[narrator, in Japanese] Various factors
determine a turquoise's value.
The value of a cut of turquoise
depends on its size, the maker,
mining site, and stone type.
[in English] So cool.
Yeah, so mine…
mine are expensive… [chuckles]
…because it's very special stone.
[♪ music ends]
Thank you.
-So rare. So rare.
-[Genta] So rare.
Yeah. And so, this one is very special
-and the mounting is very special.
-Mm-hmm.
And the stone above the turquoise
-is called paraíba tourmaline.
-[Genta] Mmm. Paraíba. Uh-huh.
-[in Japanese] How is it?
-It looks fantastic on you.
-Wait, are you being sarcastic?
-What? I'm serious.
Hey, hey. You've got a smile.
-I mean it. You're killing it.
-Hey, be serious, please.
-You're still smiling.
-I'm being serious. It looks great.
Really, though. You're rocking it.
[laughs]
-You serious? You're not joking?
-Dead serious. It looks great.
-[in English] Yes, this please. Uh-huh.
-Yeah. Yes. It's you.
[♪ gentle music playing]
[in Japanese] I bought it.
I can't believe it.
You actually bought it.
But I felt a connection with it.
-Yes, you instantly connected.
-Yes.
We want to buy something matching
then take good care of them.
[clerk, in English]
Um, because all of these are pretty…
-[Shime, Genta] Mmm. Mmm. Mm-hmm.
-…pretty similar.
And, uh, yeah, it's, um…
-It would be very nice 'cause then…
-Yes.
…you can always make something
and all of you can wear one thing.
I wear a piece next to my skin.
[Genta] Whoa. Huh.
It's next to my skin.
-And so, many people like this type.
-[Genta] Mm-hmm.
-And the ancient tribes…
-[Genta] Yes. Uh-huh.
…that use turquoise always said,
"Wear turquoise against the skin."
-[Genta] Uh-huh.
-[clerk] So some people like to do that.
-I always do myself.
-[Shime] Mmm.
[in Japanese] We can always wear them
under our stage outfits.
We can keep it on
when we're performing too.
Right? If we have a chance
-to group up along the way on this trip…
-Great idea. You can give it to them.
-Right? Right?
-We can all wear them.
I wonder if necklaces
are the safest choice.
-They're the perfect gifts.
-Yes.
It's a feasible choice. So then…
-These must all be the same type of rock.
-[Shime] Yes. Yes, yes.
-[Genta] See?
-Wanna pick seven out of these necklaces?
-Yeah, I'll do that. Okay.
-Yeah.
-This will be a perfect fit for us. TJ.
-I agree.
-Now, shall we start by choosing ours?
-Yes, let's do it.
-You pick mine, and I pick yours?
-Great idea.
-Let's choose the one that suits us best.
-Nice.
Out of these, right?
I picked mine out.
For me… Give me a minute.
I'm down to two choices.
Okay, I chose yours.
-Let's point simultaneously.
-Got it.
-Ready…
-Huh? What? Wait, wait. No way.
-[chuckles]
This one.
-Ah, ah. If it were down to two, I'd pick…
-I see. Yeah, yeah.
I want this one too.
-[Genta] It's cute. Cute, cute, cute.
-It's cute, right?
I'd like to learn
-more about this stone.
-We want to learn.
[clerk, in English]
Okay, this one is from the Bisbee mine.
Bisbee mine.
The one that closed in 1974.
-They both are from the same mine. Yeah.
-[Genta] Right.
[in Japanese]
The patterns are only slightly different.
-I love that.
-The patterns are different,
-but they're the same type of rock.
-Their significance is the same.
-They resonate all the same.
-Oh, I love that.
What if we buy these?
-I'm sold. Let's get these.
-Yeah. Let's do it.
Let's say this one is for you, Shime-chan…
-Okay. Mm-hmm.
-…and this one's mine.
-[Genta] Oh, this is wonderful.
-[Shime] Yes, it's so precious.
-Whoa, hold on. Wait.
-Okay, I have my pick.
[Shime] I know which one I'm getting.
-A one, two.
-[Genta] Whoa.
-[Shime] Whoa, whoa, whoa.
[clerk, in English]
This one is from a different mine.
-[Genta] Oh.
-This one is from Blue Gem.
[Shime, Genta] Blue Gem.
[clerk] Yeah, this one is Bisbee.
-[Genta] Ah.
-[Shime] Bisbee.
[in Japanese] This… one.
[in English] Everything you select here
-is Bisbee.
-Bisbee.
-I think you have selected very good.
-Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
You do a good job for your buddies.
-Oh, nice. Thank you.
-Wow. Wow.
-Good buddy.
-[in Japanese] Hear that?
[in English] Nice.
[in Japanese]
Want to choose from the same set?
-[Genta] I mean, since they have these.
-[Shime] Yeah.
-[Genta] Then let's do it.
-[Shime] Okay.
-Gen.
-Me.
-Noel.
Umi.
-Then Chaka.
-Chaka…
Machu's is this one.
Chaka.
-Then, Shime.
-Shime.
-Shizu.
[in English] Perfect.
-[in Japanese] They match!
-[in English] Oh, my gosh.
-This is Travis Japan.
-Travis Japan.
All right.
-So fun. And also…
-Yeah.
-…more in love with the turquoise. Yeah.
-[clerk] Good. Good.
-Yeah. Turquoise is a wonderful stone.
-[Genta] Yes.
There is something for every person.
[Genta] Mm-hmm, hmm, hmm, hmm.
-I so love it.
-[Shime] Thank you.
-Nice to see you like it.
-Nice, but thank you so much.
-Thank you so much.
-[in Japanese] Thank you.
-Thank you.
-[in English] Thank you so much.
[in Japanese]
Yeah. We got gifts for all the members.
Yes, something for everyone.
-I hope they like it.
-Yeah. I'm certain they will.
-[Shime] We're all done.
-[Machu] You're done?
-Got yourself something nice?
-[Shime] Yeah, it's really nice.
[♪ playful music playing]
Whoa, this is nice. I love it.
-Isn't it cute?
-It's very pretty.
And look, we're matching.
This one's mine.
And here's mine.
-Huh? What about mine?
-We match.
-Lemme see, lemme see.
-Matchy-matchy.
-Whoa, it's cute.
-Isn't it?
Whoa.
-It's very cute.
-Matchy-matchy.
-We're matchy-matchy.
-Hey,
-what about me?
-Aren't they cute?
Yeah!
-Did you get me one? Okay.
-You wear it next to your skin.
-What do you mean, next to your skin?
-So, don't wear it over shirts.
-It should be against your skin.
-Okay, okay.
-It wards off evil.
-Matchy-matchy.
-What about mine?
-Isn't it cute?
-It is. It's super cute.
-It's cute, isn't it?
-[chuckling] Isn't it cute?
-It's super cute.
-Hey, what about me?
-Isn't this great?
-Is there one for me?
-Yeah, we match.
-[Genta] Hmm?
-Where's mine?
You like it?
[all] Really? Yeah!
[all chuckle, laugh, whoop]
Yeah!
Are you serious? It's for me?
I'll sit by you.
Yeah.
-We're all matchy-matchy, all matching.
-I can match with you guys?
Hey, I was really lonely.
I'm the one who wanted a hat though.
The hat's cute.
-Doesn't it look great?
-Oh, a hat.
-Yeah. See?
-Isn't it cute?
Yeah. And it suits you.
-I love this.
-Isn't it cute?
That hat?
Whoa, it looks great on you.
-It's great.
-Hold on…
-Is it handmade?
-It's completely handmade.
-Really?
-Yeah.
-How was it made?
-That's amazing.
Yeah. The hatmaker walked through
the entire process with me.
And it's… What? Oh, did you add this band?
Yeah. You can pick the band too.
-Whoa, whoa.
-Whoa.
This is your treasure.
And we had encounters
with wonderful people.
-You're right.
-Yeah.
-It's true.
-Today was great.
I loved meeting the hatmaker.
-He showed me how it's made.
-That's for sure.
Everyone's been so kind to us.
-The jeweler was wonderful too.
-He was very kind.
-This city is remarkable.
-Yeah, I agree.
-Well, shall we walk?
-Yeah.
-Let's head back to the car.
-This was the best. Seriously.
-I'm glad.
-[Machu] Yeah.
I had a blast today.
-[Machu] Today was so special.
-[Shime] Right?
[Machu] This is such a wonderful city.
[♪ music ends]
[Noel, in Japanese]
The America the members haven't seen.
Which city should I head to next?
[♪ gentle music playing]
Hot springs.
I wonder if they know that there
are hot springs in the United States.
Pagosa Springs.
"Pagosa" means "the healing water"
in the language of the Natives.
The Native Americans believed
these springs had the power
to cure illnesses and injuries.
I want everyone to have a moment
of rejuvenation for their mind and body.
[♪ music ends]
[Genta] Want to pour a cup for each other?
[Shime] Yeah, good idea.
Look, it's dripping.
Dripping now.
This is great. I've always wanted
to try something like this.
Cheers.
-Cheers.
-Oh, phew. Yum!
-Ah. Sweet.
Man. Let's take in this view too.
-[Machu] The view is fantastic.
-[Shime] Yup.
[Machu] Oh, wait.
Is that a lake back there?
-[Shime] Whoa!
-[Genta chuckles]
[Shime] This feels otherworldly.
-[Genta] What?
-[Shime] Let's see.
"Today, you will visit a hot spring area
that the Natives believed
could cure illnesses and wounds."
"Pagosa… Springs."
-Whoa, I can't wait.
-Hot springs? This will be great.
-Right?
-Wait. That's all for today?
Hmm? There's nothing else on this page.
-Wait. We're enjoying a soak? That's it?
-Yep.
Really, it doesn't say anything else.
Whoa.
-[shouting] Yes!
-[Shime chuckles]
[chuckling] Wait. Machu ran the other way.
-No, stop! Wrong direction!
-Stop!
-You're going the wrong way!
-It'll take forever if you go that way!
-Wait up! That's… definitely not the way.
-Hey, wait…
-Why did he bolt towards the stop sign?
-Right?
[Genta] Look, he stopped.
He's just standing there.
[Machu] Woo-wee!
-[laughing] This guy…
-[laughing]
He said, "Woo-wee."
[Genta] I've never seen such an open view.
[Machu] The view is unreal.
[Genta] It feels great.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
I wonder what kind
of hot springs they are?
-I can't wait.
-Me too.
I'm excited for it.
[Shime] That's the only time we get to go
with all seven of us.
Yeah.
-Or only some of us do.
-True.
You've got a point.
[Machu] We made it.
-[Shime] At last.
-[in English] "Welcome to Pagosa Springs."
[Shime, in Japanese] Nice!
[Genta] We made it.
The town…
-[Shime] …looks different from Santa Fe.
-[Genta] Yes.
[Machu] This place has a different feel
than Santa Fe.
[Shime] The atmosphere here
is completely different.
[Genta] I see a hot spring over there.
-[Genta] They're wearing swimming suits.
-[Machu] Oh, really? Where?
[Genta] The little kids.
[narrator, in English]
Pagosa Springs, Colorado.
[in Japanese]
This is a beautiful city surrounded by
the abundant nature of San Juan Mountains.
All over town, you will spot
these volcano-shaped mounds
of crystallized minerals
that have built up over time.
-[Machu] Here we are.
-We're here!
We made it.
-Whoa, whoa!
-I'm excited for the hot springs.
-Whoa, look!
-[laughs]
-This will be a blast!
-Whoa.
-Isn't this crazy?
-No way.
What? It's a pool.
-This is so nice. Let's go take a plunge.
-[in English] Hi!
-[in Japanese] This is amazing.
-Whoa, this is gonna be a blast.
[Genta] What if we just jump in like this?
[Machu laughs] Yeah, let's dive in.
-[Genta] Okay.
-[Shime] Yeah, wanna go?
Is this a river?
-[in English] Hi!
-Hi!
-[Machu] Watch your step!
-[Genta laughs]
[in Japanese]
They're having a great day. [laughs]
-I want to try it.
-That's gotta be a blast.
This is… [chuckling] …something else.
It's the best.
This really feels
like a summer vacation now.
-Yeah, this is fantastic.
-Seriously though, thank you, Noel!
-Yeah, thank you, Noel.
-Thanks from the bottom of our hearts.
-Whoa, it's pretty in here.
-Whoa, what a nice place.
-[resort clerk, in English] Hi.
-Hello.
-Hi.
-[resort clerk] Hi. Welcome.
-Nice to meet you.
Hello.
Thank you.
Ah, yeah, can we check in?
We would love to check you in.
-Thank you so much.
-Welcome to The Springs Resort.
-So, we have…
-Yeah.
-So, these are your wristbands…
-Thank you.
-…and they act as your room keys.
-You are welcome. Absolutely.
-Thanks so much.
[Genta] So, can you tell us, um,
more the resort?
More about the resort? Absolutely.
So, we have the deepest
geothermal hot spring.
And all of our pools… We have
over 50 pools and water features.
And you get to soak
in our geothermal mineral water.
And you get to explore all the different
wellness activities and offerings.
-So…
-Nice.
…there's a lot to explore
here on the property.
And most of it is focused on ways
to get you to relax
and really rejuvenate yourself.
-[Machu] Mm-hmm.
-Thank you.
[Machu, in Japanese] Whoa. [chuckling]
Whoa, this is fantastic!
-That's a strong smell of sulfur here.
-Right?
-[in English] So, this, can you smell?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, it smells.
-Exactly.
And so you can see all the minerals
in the water.
But this is the deepest
geothermal hot spring.
-So, it is so deep…
-Uh-huh.
Uh-huh.
Have you heard
of Guinness Book of World Records?
So, this hot spring
has a very long history
of people using the water
for their health.
So even our native peoples who lived
in this area centuries ago,
they would come and this would be
a place of healing and peace.
Even if they were fighting,
-if the different tribes were fighting…
-Uh-huh.
-…they would lay down their weapons…
…and this would be a place
where they could bring their injured
or bring their sick
to be able to heal in peace.
-[Machu] Mmm.
-[Genta] Uh-huh.
And so, they have come
to be able to get that benefit.
Even if they were at war outside,
they would come here and heal together.
-Mmm. Mmm. Together.
-[resort clerk] Yeah, yeah.
They would leave their weapons
and just come to heal.
-[in Japanese] That's wonderful.
-[in English] Really? Yeah.
-Peaceful place.
-Yeah.
-[in Japanese] The hot springs must be…
-…a universal place of peace.
-That's a great point.
[in English] It's so special.
-It really is.
-Yes. Nice.
And you'll feel it
when you get in the water.
-Mm-hmm.
-You'll truly feel the benefits.
You know, not only that it's warm water,
but the minerals make such a difference
in the healing properties of the water.
Wow.
And then when you have
the different wellness activities,
-so like the aqua sound bath…
-Uh-huh.
…where we bring the Tibetan singing bowls
into the water.
You're getting the benefits of the water
and the benefits of the sound vibrations
through the water.
It's a wonderful coming together
-with a nice aqua sauna.
-Nice.
-[in Japanese] Whoa.
-Aqua sauna.
-Never heard of it.
-Wait. Can we try it out?
-[in English] Um, yes, absolutely.
-[in Japanese] Oh!
You heard her. I want to try it out.
-I love this.
-Yeah, me too.
-And aqua sound bath.
-Yeah.
-A water sound bath? Aqua…
-Aqua…
[♪ gentle music playing]
Here, here. Here.
-Holy mackerel.
-It can't get any better than this.
-This is incredible.
-Seriously.
-[Machu] Whoa, whoa. Oh, is this it?
-[Shime] Yeah.
[Genta]
This really is a natural hot spring.
Over there.
[Machu]
The tub with the overflowing water?
[Shime] Okay, okay, okay.
[♪ music ends]
[instructor, in English]
You guys ready for a sound bath?
-[band members] Yeah.
-All right.
-[Genta] First time.
-Yay. Okay, cool.
Well, I'm playing on a different set
than I normally play,
so it's kind of my first time too
with these specific bowls.
I play a different set of metal bowls
and crystal bowls, so we'll have some fun.
-[band members] Okay. Yes.
-All right.
-[in Japanese] It's time!
-Here we go!
-We're here!
-Nice.
It's warm.
-Nice and warm.
-Nice.
-It's the best.
-[whoops]
[instructor, in English] Welcome, welcome.
[in Japanese] Oh, this is great.
-I feel it.
-Nice.
-[in English] Yeah. Oh, yeah. Uh-huh.
-This smell, right?
And you'll actually see
how the vibration moves the water.
So, it's neat to see.
Especially since you are musicians.
You can really see how the sound travels
when it's in water.
[bowls chiming]
[in Japanese] I can feel the vibration.
Phew, it's strong.
[Machu] Ah.
-This is incredible.
-Whoa, amazing.
Over here too.
[bowl chiming softly]
[Shime] Whoa.
[grunts softly]
[bowls chiming]
[deep, resonant ringing]
[bowl chiming]
[chiming fades]
-[in English] Have a wonderful visit.
-Thank you.
-Thank you so much.
-Thanks, everybody.
-[in Japanese] So relaxing.
-That was a moment of pure bliss.
-The ringing sensation was surprising.
-Yeah.
There was an intense vibration underwater.
-I felt it, yeah.
-Yeah.
[♪ gentle music playing]
-[Shime] I wonder what causes it?
-That was deeply relaxing.
Whoa, whoa.
This rock must also
have beneficial properties.
-At the very beginning…
-Yeah.
-…I felt a vibration from over here.
-Me too.
I felt it too, yeah.
It came all at once.
How do I put it…
-The relaxing feeling?
-Yeah, the relaxation.
Shime mentioned
an almost hypnotic sensation.
I felt a vibration to my core.
So I took a quick peek at Shime.
[Shime, Machu laughing]
-He was like this.
-Seriously?
-I was on the brink of sleep.
-You're hilarious.
I almost dozed off.
Yeah, you were this close
to falling asleep.
[in English] Face?
If you don't have sensitive skin.
If you have sensitive skin,
I would avoid your face, but…
-Got it.
-Yes, absolutely.
-And then your armpits…
-Uh-huh.
-…and the bottom of your feet as well.
-Gotcha.
-Here.
-[in Japanese] Sick.
[Shime] Hup.
[in English]
So, we-we don't need to put on the face.
-[resort worker] No.
-Okay.
-You can if you want to.
-Body.
-Just body?
-Yes.
Okay.
-[Genta, in Japanese] Me too.
-[Machu] A first for me too.
Hah!
[Shime] Phew, that's cooling.
[♪ gentle music playing]
[resort worker, in English]
If you wanna go there…
-[Genta] All right. [chuckles]
-…that's fine.
[Genta] Is this correct?
[resort worker] That's great.
[in Japanese]
I'll apply it on my upper body and face.
Phew, cold! [grunts]
[Machu] You all applied it quickly.
[Shime] My goodness, that's cooling.
It's very…
You got something on your face.
[exclaims]
You got some here.
-It's chilling.
-Hey, don't rub the clay on my face!
Hey!
[chuckles]
I'm cooled down.
[in English] This one is a smoothie.
It's strawberry and piña colada.
[Shime] I like strawberry.
Yeah. Facing it that way.
-This one's strawberry lime shrub.
-Thank you.
-Okay.
-Okay, and this one is Asian pear.
-And the blackberry one.
-The blackberry.
-Thank you so much.
-You guys are welcome. Enjoy.
-Thank you.
-Thank you so much.
-[in Japanese] How kind.
-This is great.
Wait, I thought piña colada
was an alcoholic beverage.
-Yeah!
-Seriously?
-Let's enjoy a few sips.
-True.
-Can we?
-Shouldn't be an issue.
I've never seen
a strawberry this big before.
-That's a big one.
-Yeah, Shime.
-Strawberries are your favorite.
-Yeah, I'll give it a sip.
Yum!
It's delectable.
Is it painful?
A bit.
Yeah.
Time for a sip.
[Shime]
What's that? Is that the best smile
-you can give me?
-Yeah, it's my best smile.
[laughs]
[Genta] Come this way. Over here.
Phew, this one is cold.
It's warm! It's almost hot.
Hot!
-[Machu] I wanna try them.
-This one's just right.
Phew, cold!
Now that's warm.
[Shime] That feels nice.
[Genta] Hmm, this is great.
Oh, this hits the spot.
-This is great.
-Yeah.
I'm loving this.
Oh, whoa.
Whoa!
-Oh, wow!
-What a view.
This is so relaxing.
[♪ gentle music continues]
[♪ music ends]
Oh, crap!
-Hey.
-Huh?
-Hey, guys.
-Yeah?
I got a message from Team A.
Really?
-They sent a video?
-Yeah.
Hey, guys!
-Hello!
-Hey, everyone.
[♪ funky music playing]
We are currently at the Arches!
We're here at the Arches.
-Where are you guys?
-Wonder where you could be.
-Let us know.
-Tell us!
Where are you?
[all] Ah! Oh, oh…
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
Looks like… they're in some mountains.
-The Arches?
-Arches…
-They're in the middle of the mountains.
-What a magnificent view.
-What are they doing out there?
-It looks incredible.
-Yeah.
-Let's send a video back.
-A video for them.
-Let's reply.
-Okay.
-Hi.
-[both] Hi.
-Hey, everyone.
-It's been a while, guys.
-Long time no see.
-It's been forever.
Hope you're doing well.
-We're enjoying ourselves.
-How are you?
We're at a hot spring resort
called Pagosa Springs.
That's right.
Are we having the best time of our life?
-We are!
-We're having a blast!
We're enjoying the summer vibes.
-These are natural hot springs.
-Yes. Hot springs!
It's so relaxing.
-We're at the hot springs.
-This is so great.
Yes, these springs are natural.
And they provide alcohol!
-There are 50 types of hot springs.
-We're loving it.
-Yeah.
-50!
And they're open 24 hours.
-This is the best.
-We're having a blast.
This is the best summer vacation
of our lives.
-Yeah!
-Stay safe on your travels, guys.
Good luck out there!
-We'll message you again.
-We can't wait to see you guys.
-[Machu] See you soon!
-That looks really nice.
[♪ music ends]
Let's hear all about it when we see them.
-[Shizu] Good idea.
-Yeah.
-We've gotta ask about the hot springs.
[Shizu] We've gotta hear about their trip.
-We're on the move today?
-That's right. We're traveling today.
-Right.
-It's written in the notebook.
Where are we going today?
There it is.
What?
"Moab to Monument Valley."
-Monument Valley…
-Never heard of it.
-Maybe that's what it's called.
-…must be the name of the place.
Monument Valley, Monument Valley.
-Monument Valley.
-We're not quite…
-Currently, we are right here.
-Where are we? We're there?
-That's where we are.
-That's right.
Good.
-[in English] Near, near, near.
-Near?
[in Japanese] Found it!
-There you have it.
-"Monument Valley."
-[Chaka] Moab… Yeah.
-[Umi] And from here…
-[Shizu] We travel all the way south.
-We keep traveling south.
-[Umi] We head south.
-[Shizu] The entire way.
-Even more.
-[Umi] Then go this way.
-[Shizu] It's miles away from here.
-[Umi] You're right.
Well then, let's start driving
to Monument Valley.
-Is it that way?
-Which direction is it?
-[in English] Let's go!
-Yeah!
[♪ epic music playing]
[Noel, in Japanese] This must be what
America looked like before its discovery.
[narrator, in English]
Goosenecks State Park, Utah.
[in Japanese]
The winding river in this panoramic view
is named after the graceful curve
of a goose's neck.
Three hundred meters below
these rocky cliffs is the San Juan river,
which was carved over eons
by the water flowing through.
[Shizu] What?
-[Umi] What the heck is this?
-Whoa, what's this?
This is remarkable.
Amazing!
This can't be real.
Whoa!
[Chaka] Is it a river?
[Umi] Must be.
[Shizu whoops]
[Chaka] What an incredible view.
-How on earth did this come to be?
-[Shizu laughs]
-This must be what Grand Canyon is like…
-What a sight.
-…though I've never been.
-Yeah.
-The water carved the canyon.
-I wonder what this river is called.
Is that sand, or rocks in front of us?
-I can't tell.
-Yeah.
The river must have reached
this high at one point.
Maybe.
[Shizu] This is unreal.
[♪ epic music continues]
[♪ music ends]
[hissing]
[♪ funky music playing]
[Noel] Don't be amazed just yet.
There's an even more majestic view
waiting up ahead.
Right there.
It's coming into view.
That over there is Monument Valley.
There, a sight the members
have never seen unfolds.
Translated by Megumi Hunter